believe not least our sixth and final
honoree of the night
the 13th class of the Cleveland Indian
alcohol of Fame we would like to adopt
councilman Mike England
and in recognizing him tonight is Joe
Simon
Applause
congratulations there's a great saying
in Slovenia
and that means always always speak the
truth and then leave immediately after
thanks everybody
guys tonight we are honoring somebody
who really needs no introduction
he's someone who's being honored for his
incredible dedication tonight he's being
honored on behalf of every Slovenian
American city of Cleveland
slovenians like our Council General
Council General Guinea an ambassador's
aide who's working here in Cleveland the
highest rank ing Diplomat in the state
of Ohio our own Bishop Bishop Alessia
and even Beijing Shaw who reminds me
every day that Slovenia is the only
nation in the world with the word love
in it hahaha
folks
tonight and I'm going to ask Mother
Cooksey for a dispensation I tried doing
some math and it's not my forte but I
want to do Mike polensic like numbers
my classic has been elected and
re-elected 15 times in the city of Lisa
he has served executive
distinction
2340 weeks
when you look at
the career he has looked at and reviewed
000 pieces of legislation
he has made over 207 000 votes and in
the course of his lifetime has supported
over
22.5 billion dollars in the budget of
the city of Cleveland
's life have voted for him and I would
tell you this because I used to work
with him he has received over 819 000
calls and I'm willing to bet he has
returned every single one of them
landmarks legislation which actually
makes it impossible to tear Downs
Cleveland historic churches schools and
structures
he also fought
and he made sure that the Collinwood rec
center was built
that's great
I'm not sure the good Lord though really
cares about those numbers
how many senior citizens has Mike
blessed helped get their gas or lights
turned
how many young people has he given a job
reference to to get a job
and how many times has he made our
streams Street safer for every single
person who lives here so why is he being
honored as a selenium yes he's a hard
worker but so are our friends from the
Indian Community
sure he is determined but so are our
friends from the Italian Community
I think tonight the reason the thing
that makes him the Slovenian honoree is
that life keeps working and hoping in
spite of how hard life in Cleveland
sounds
there's a saying that is said by one of
our greatest Slovenian poets and the
saying is this
[Music]
in all of our beliefs and faiths there
is only one God and that is the god of
love I'd go and say we love you come on
up to be abducted
thank you John you didn't listen to me I
hope I'll make it short and sweet okay
hang up
late if my father reminded me because
the Cavs game on tonight
and then my my son Andrew said dad I
gotta get up for work tomorrow
I've attended many of these older than
years and when I look out at the crowd
Following the Leader of a very ethnic
racial cultural group for the city in
Cleveland Beyond I say thank you again
for your care and your concern for our
nationalities and across the boards
um what a wonderful thing about again
I've tended it so many times over the
years and I wish to thank Dan and Debbie
Hanson as well as reporting committee
members and installing this Connor
behind me
the other outstanding inductees for
their Heritage Pierre Pat
Joyce sudason and mayor Georgine we
engagement are blessed to be a wonderful
Cosmopolitan community and holds us so
many different ethnic racial and
religious groups and organizations
being a proud member of the Slovenian
Community I learned that an early age
the meaning of hard work sacrifice and
respecting one's heritage
born in the Glenville neighborhood and
raising cows that may be keenly aware of
the world that we all play in making our
city a better place
I think mother Doreen is still in my
siblings and I and my siblings the need
to get involved to be to participate in
school activities or in the community in
general is that's what I believe
it was through her love and advice and
the support and love of my late
grandparents that I understood with the
meaning of sacrifice and hard work love
mom is a single parent
raised four of us in a two-bedroom home
on Saint Clair Avenue
she worked extremely hard to provide for
her children
during that time I was introduced to the
importance of two Slovenian Homes
located in a harlemen community
those two homes and those students were
being holding power became my home away
from home
I saw firsthand my brothers and sisters
with the Slovenian Community joined
together
and help one another promoting their
Heritage and in making their Community
the best it could be
I see that demonstrated weekly our
brothers and sisters Saint Mary's an
assumption Church in Powell where I'm a
proud parishion I want to thank Father
John Lucy for being very simply MRT the
child is
Bishop we got a great three stop there
don't mess with them okay
so I ran about it to be inducted as a
Slovenian artery into the Hall of Fame
however I would be remiss if I did not
thank all the folks who supported me
over the years kind of look Community is
very diverse a lot of people don't
realize it oh so I gotta tell you
there's Joe Mills nobody counts
of Eastern European the sun in this city
has ever received the support that I've
had my brothers and sisters invite you
as well as my brothers and sisters into
Croatia Lebanese hybrid Italian Jewish
and live the way to begin that it
historically comprised the Commonwealth
neighborhood
they've adopted me and I love each and
every one of them
sign language to thank the members of my
family who to share this Joy with me
tonight I'd like to introduce my
daughter Lisa
um
and my son Andrew his girlfriend Kim is
I like the rest of the king
was math
could not make it I also wish to thank
some of my closest friends who are here
tonight and support this wonderful plan
I'd like to thank my assistant Mary
Louise Justin Bailey husband Tim
Potter and upgrade this guy
high school together
and this time
you're finally recognize my dear friend
because of General Republican alleged
Jerry and my other dear friend carry
Castle for Lithuanian people who
believes because of what they've done on
behalf of our community to Dan dummy
once again and all who've gathered here
tonight in Europe you've demonstrated 40
Years of how a work business or the rich
cultural ethnic and racial diversity of
our greater City and region we must all
strive to preserve maintain and respect
each other's culture and hear it and I
got to tell Alex when since you left the
Plain Dealer I without having that
Mosaic in there there's been a great
loss for us in this in this entire week
to do that I want to help
so again thank you all I hope I was
short and sweet God bless and please
stay safe
thank you foreign